本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
那朵云看起来像一只花栗鼠
That cloud looks like a chipmunk.
吐出了一架飞机
Barfing an airplane.
确实是
It does.
呃  那朵云看起来像  呃  一朵云
Uh, that cloud looks like... uh, a cloud.
-什么啊  -汤普森  拜托不要干什么都倒数第一
- What? - Thompson, stop being the worst at everything.
不好意思啦  小伙伴们
Sorry, guys.
快看那云
Look at the clouds.
唔  那朵云看起来像一个巨大的心形气球
Ooh! That cloud looks like a big heart-shaped balloon.
云没有颜色  那就是个气球
Clouds don't come in colors. That is a balloon.
对了  是伍德斯迪克音乐节
Oh, dude, it's the Woodstick festival.
（注：此处戏仿"Woodstock Rock Festival"，伍德斯托克音乐节）
等等  伍德什么
Wait. The Wood what?
这是一个每年举办的室外音乐节
It's this annual outdoor concert
全俄勒冈州的新晋独立乐队都会参加
featuring Oregon's up-and-coming indie bands.
他们都会来
They're all coming.
室内围巾  全木纹  爱神
Scarves Indoors, Wood grain on Everything, Love God.
你可能在那个网络神片里见过他
You've probably seen him in that viral video.
准备好感受今晚的爱了吗
Who's ready for love tonight?
希望没人拍
I hope nobody's filming this.
喔  是那种真正的演唱会式的音乐节吗
Whoa, like a real concert concert?
我还  我还从来没去过这样的音乐节呢
I've-- I've never actually been to one of those before.
那是因为你从来没有找到一群志同道合的小伙伴陪你一起去
That's because you've never had an awesome crew to roll with before.
快点啊  汤普森
Come on, Thompson.
舔那块海绵  舔那块海绵
Lick that sponge. Lick that sponge.
噢  我简直不敢相信他真的这么做了
Oh! I can't believe he's doing it.
他在干什么啊
What is he doing?
我们带你一起玩
When you're with us, you're in.
幽灵的声音
Ghosty sounds.
墓地中的幽灵的声音
Cemetery ghosty sounds!
是从那个打开的墓穴中传出来的
It's coming from that open grave.
-你去看  -不  你去看
- You look. - No. You look.
汤普森  去看看
Thompson, go look.
呵  汤普森的正确用法
Heh. Nice use of Thompson.
注视亡灵
Gaze upon death.
注视亡灵  注视亡灵
Gaze upon death. Gaze upon death.
注视亡灵
Gaze upon death.
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
■
时间轴： WaitinZ
翻译： Peace  莫莉什么的  战忽局副局座
■
校订  后期： Enpistu  WaitinZ
怪诞小镇  第二季第九集
Gravity Falls  S02E09  The Love God
呃  这甚至比我想象的还要诡异
Ugh! It's even creepier than I expected.
她为什么要离开我
Why did she leave me?
罗比
Robbie?
温蒂
Wendy!
嗨  最近怎么样
Hey, what's up?
我就在这个坟墓里逛逛  你懂的
Just hanging out in this grave, you know.
很正常啊  对我来说很普通的一天
Regular. Regular day for me.
伙计  我们好像已经有一百万年没见过你了
Whoa, dude, we haven't seen you in, like, a million years.
你去哪里了
Where have you been?
你不会还在为我们的分手哀伤吧
You're not still mourning our break-up, are you?
什么  绝对没有
What? No way.
罗比  我们分开都那么久了
Robbie, we split up forever ago.
你为了我跳进坟墓我很感动
It's really sweet you'd throw yourself into a grave for me,
但是  兄弟  是时候放下了
but, man, time to move on.
什么  我早就放下了
What? I've totally moved on.
温蒂  我好想你
Wendy, I miss you so much
我永远不会忘记你
I'll never move on.
永远不会
Never ever
此温蒂非彼温蒂  另一个温蒂
That was a different Wendy. Unrelated Wendy.
小伙伴们  真是越来越尴尬了
Dude, this is getting really awkward.
是啊  墓地原本很有趣的
Yeah, the cemetery used to be fun.
现在真是压抑
Now it's just depressing.
等等  各位  他很痛苦
Wait. You guys, he's in pain.
我们不能把他丢在这里
We can't just ditch him here.
快走吧  梅宝
Come on, Mabel.
那是罗比
It's Robbie.
但他在受苦
But he's suffering.
知道有人在悲伤之中  我又怎么开心得起来
How can I be happy if I know someone else is sad?
这完全违背我的幸福表格
It totally throws off my Happiness Chart.
大家都开心吗？
梅宝  相信我
Mabel, trust me.
如果说这个暑假让我学到什么的话
If there's one thing I've learned this summer,
就是不要在毫无意义的爱情闹剧中纠结
it's not to get mixed up in needless romantic drama.
除此之外  我们终于融入温蒂的朋友圈了
Besides, we're finally in with Wendy's friends.
罗比走后  才有了社交平衡
With Robbie gone, there's a good social balance.
可能我们就应该顺其自然的  你懂吗
Maybe we should just let a good thing be, you know?
吃了我算了
Just eat me already, man.
啊  我只是多愁善感一下
Aaah! I was just being dramatic.
快停下  嗷  嗷
Quit it. Ow! Ow!
我的脸  臭秃鹰
My face. Vulture!
噢  天哪
Oh, man.
很抱歉让你们看到了那一幕
I'm sorry you guys had to see that.
你知道罗比需要什么吗
You know, what Robbie needs?
一个新女友
A new girl.
爱情就像口香糖
Romance is like gum.
一旦味道变淡了  你就再嚼一个
Once it's lost its flavor, you just cram another one in.
梅宝  这事儿可没那么简单
Mabel, it's not that easy.
如果你是这个世界上最棒的红娘就有这么简单
It is if you're the world's greatest matchmaker.
我的顾客没有一个不满意的
I've never had an unhappy customer.
你看苏斯和梅洛蒂
Like Soos and Melody.
看这个
Watch this.
我正在走下真正的楼梯
Walking down some actual stairs.
看起来酷吗
Did it look cool?
酷毙了
The coolest.
牵手成功
Match made!
当然  还有摇摇和冈珀斯
And then, of course, there's Waddles and Gompers.
新婚
牵手成功
Match made.
这方法对猪和山羊可能奏效
That might work for a goat and a pig,
但罗比这个案例可就希望渺茫了
but Robbie's a hopeless case.
希望渺茫的案例  诶
Hopeless case, e-e-e-e-eh...?
给白色大猩猩带上彩虹假发
Putting a rainbow wig on a big white gorilla
搞什么
What the...?
噢  不  热气球
Oh, no. Hot air balloons.
死飞车
Fixed gear bikes.
在宽阔的大路上歌唱
Singing 'bout the open road
我的凉鞋露脚趾
My sandals are so open-toed
民谣歌曲  是伍德斯迪克音乐节
Folk music! It's the Woodstick Festival!
苏斯  锁好小屋藏好我的衬衫
Soos! Lock down the Shack and hide my shirts
别让任何人扎染它们
before anyone tie-dyes them!
他们很慢
They're slow.
我应该能打下来几个
I can probably take a few down.
等等  派恩斯先生
Wait, Mr. Pines!
我一直在想
I've been thinking.
每年都有音乐节
Every year this festival comes by
而你每年却都在回避那些潜在的顾客
and every year you shun what could be potential customers.
你真觉得我能从这些
You really think I can make money off of these
不劳而获  只啃蔬菜的怪胎身上赚到钱
free-loading, kale-munching freak shows?
你只要弄明白什么能吸引他们就行
You just got to figure out what appeals to them.
我该怎么把年轻人吸引过来呢
Hmm. How do I appeal to young people?
看来年轻人喜欢热气球啊  诶
So young people are into hot air balloons, e-e-e-e-eh?
好的  梅宝
All right, Mabel.
罗比的心已破碎
Robbie's a broken teacup,
你要帮他重新找回幸福
and you're going to piece him back together.
瓦伦蒂诺  殡仪馆
如果你死了，那么你现在已经到家了
好吧  可能会很刺激
Okay, this could get intense.
你好呀
Howdy doo!
祝你今天愉快
Happy day!
太刺激了
It is intense!
你们是罗比的父母吗
You're Robbie's parents?
我一直以为他是
I always thought he was, like,
被悲伤的狼群抚养长大的
raised by sad wolves or something.
噢  好吧  他不喜欢说起我们
Oh, well, he doesn't like to talk about us.
他总是说我们作为殡葬主管性格有些过度开朗了
He always says we're too cheerful for funeral directors.
快请进  快请进
Come in. Come in.
饼干拼盘
Cracker platter?
噢  我没时间吃饼干  不好意思
Oh, no time for crackers. Sorry.
我是来让罗比振作起来的
I'm here to cheer Robbie up.
满嘴饼干渣可干不了这活儿
Cannot have a dry cracker mouth for that.
罗比・史戴西・瓦伦蒂诺
Robbie Stacey Valentino!
有个小姑娘想见你
There's little a girl here to see you.
你上楼吧
You go on up.
可以帮忙把他的午饭带给他吗
And could you bring him his lunch?
女士  我喜欢你的风格
Lady, I like your style.
你知道谁穿那件毛衣会好看吗
You know who would look good in a sweater like that?
格雷伯森夫人的遗体
Mrs. Grabelson's remains!
那是绝对的
Oh, absolutely!
罗比  是我梅宝
Robbie, it's Mabel!
谁
Who?
还记得我吗  我是女版的迪普
Remember me? I'm like Girl Dipper.
走开
Ugh, go away.
我听到“请进”了哦
I heard a "come in."
听着  小屁孩  这里不欢迎派恩斯家的人
Listen, kid, nobody in the Pines family is welcome here.
你可别忘了  你那愚蠢的弟弟
In case you forgot, your stupid brother
原谅我
亲爱的温蒂
就是毁掉我生活的人
is the one who ruined my life!
所以梅宝就是那个来弥补你的人
And Mabel's the one who's gonna fix it.
听着  罗比  我以前一直以为你是一个怪异的混蛋
Listen, Robbie, I always used to see you as a creepy jerk.
像是人形的老鼠药
Like the human version of rat poison.
呃  继续
Uh, go on.
但当我今天在墓地看到你时
But when I saw you in the cemetery today,
我意识到  罗比并不是个坏人
I realized, Robbie's not a bad guy.
他只是一个需要关爱的心碎之人
He's just a heartbroken soul who needs love
而且还需要有指手套
and gloves with fingers.
嘿  无指手套看起来超酷的
Hey, fingerless gloves look awesome.
才没有呢
No, they don't.
罗比  你需要的不过是个好红娘
Robbie, you just need a good matchmaker.
我保证我会帮你找到真爱
I guarantee I'll find you true love,
让你的悲伤一去不返
or twice your sadness back.
如果我说好  你会离开我的房间吗
If I say yes, will you leave my room?
我保证
I guarantee it.
好了  重力泉  谁想和罗比约会呢
Okay, Gravity Falls, who wants to go out with Robbie?
好吧  懒苏珊  太老
Okay. Lazy Susan, too old.
格兰达  太年轻
Grenda, too young.
多头熊
Multi-Bear?
我把你放在可能区
I'm putting you in the "maybe" pile.
谁可以呢  谁可以呢
Who could it be? Who could it be?
未来下一对？
怎么了  冈珀斯
What's that, Gompers?
是我们认识的人吗
Someone we already know?
但是有谁会跟罗比一样
But who could possibly be superficial
又肤浅又是个哥特控呢
and gothy enough for--
太对了  就是这样
Of course, that's it!
你们俩真不愧是国民情侣啊
You two really are America's favorite power couple.
再来几包  再来几包
More snacks! More snacks!
再来几包
More snacks!
多谢你们把我拉入伙
I'm just happy to be included.
哈  这招太妙了
Ha! This is brilliant.
把零食偷渡进演唱会现场的完美方案
The perfect way to sneak cheap snacks into the concert.
多亏了迪普的好主意
And it was all Dipper's idea.
呼  太棒啦
Whoo! Nice.
干得漂亮
Well done. Ideas!
年轻人  你有伟人的气质
Kid, I sense greatness in you.
噢  是吗  这我可不太
Oh, well, I don't know about--
了不起
Greatness!
好吧  那么现在  大家都回家
All right, now, everyone go home
做好去演唱会的准备
and finish getting ready for the concert.
嘿  别傻等着了  谭宝儿
Hey, don't wait up, Tambers.
不准叫我谭宝儿
Don't call me Tambers.
真不愧是谭宝儿
Classic Tambers.
谭布丽  你  我  约会
"Tambry. You. Me. Date.
带上点愉悦心情
"Bring that sweet, sweet bod.
某个暗恋你的人
Your secret admirer."
一场罗曼史就要拉开帷幕啦  懒苏珊
Love is about to happen, Lazy Susan.
好好学学
Watch and learn.
呃  罗比
Ugh! Robbie?
你就是暗恋我的那个人吗
You're my secret admirer?
谭布丽  呃
Tambry? Ugh!
这就是相信一个小屁孩的下场
This is just what I get for trusting a toddler.
听着  我看咱俩绝对没戏
Listen, I don't think this is gonna work out.
和一个老熟人约会
Dating somebody I already know?
搞得我跟破罐破摔似的
It's kind of like admitting defeat.
说得好像我对你有兴趣一样
Um, way to assume I'm even interested.
谭布丽  说真的
Tambry, let's be real.
我要是想约你  我早就约了
If I wanted to date you, I would have done it already.
我跟你可不是同一层次的
I'm just a little out of your league.
哟  这不会是芥末吧
Whoa, is that mustard?
可不能浪费了这好东西
Don't want to waste that bad boy.
状态更新
Status update.
与反社会宅男相亲中
On blind date with sociopath.
当然了  掏出手机刷微博吧
Oh, sure. Bring out the phone.
真不愧是谭宝儿
Classic Tambers.
嘿  能给我来份辣薯条吗
Hey, can I get some chili fries?
打包带走
To go.
什么  这怎么可能呢
What? How is this possible?
我可是史上最棒的红娘啊
I'm supposed to be the best matchmaker ever.
听到那声音没
Did you hear that? Did you hear that?
我们快去看看  快走吧
Let's go. Let's go.
你们做好准备坠入爱河了吗
Who's ready to fall in love tonight?
爱神大人
Love God!
没错  就是我
That's what they call me.
今晚我们要改写历史
We're rewriting history tonight,
先从你们开始
and it starts with you and you.
爱情如假包换  触手可及
Love is real and it's in your face!
敢问您的芳名  我的天使
What's your name, you little angel?
玛莉提丝
Meredith.
玛莉提丝  玛莉提丝  现在问题来了
Meredith, Meredith, we got a problem.
那边那个帅哥是你的真命天子
That cutie right there is your soulmate
但是你们有缘无分
and you're living without him.
天哪  不
Oh, no.
我该如何是好
What do I do?
主动出击吧  姑娘  你明知道你喜欢他
Get it, girl. You know what you love.
啪  牵手成功
Pow! Match made!
我一定要弄清楚他是怎么做到的
I must know how this works!
你好啊  爱神先生
Hi. Love God?
我是梅宝  你的粉丝
Mabel here. Big fan.
我必须说  那真是我见过的
Can I just say, that was some of the finest matchmaking
最神奇的做媒技巧
I've ever seen?
求求你告诉我  你是怎么做到的
Can you please, please, please tell me your secret?
这个嘛  我就跟你直说了吧
Well, between you and me, let's just say,
我得到这个绰号可不是偶然哦
my name's not exactly a coincidence.
我的爱神啊
Oh. My. Love God.
你真的是爱神吗
Are you an actual Love God?
实际上我就是个小天使
Call me a cherub.
现在网上相亲为我分担了不少工作
The Internet pretty much does my job for me nowadays,
所以我终于有时间玩摇滚乐了
so I've taken some time to focus on my rock career.
嘣  我的录音带
Boom. Cassette.
嘣  送你啦
Boom. For you.
喔  太棒了
Oh! That's... great.
这么说  你能让任何东西相爱吗
So anyway, can you make anything fall in love?
比方说  那条蛇和那只獾
Like that snake and that badger?
啊  这个  我也不太确定
Hmm. Ah, gee, I don't know.
说不定没那么容
That might be kind of hard to--
咔嘣  牵手成功
Ka-boom! Match made!
它们俩会生出小獾蛇哒
They're gonna make a snadger.
你到底是怎么做到的
How you doing that?
用爱情魔药啊  亲  我这有好多种呢
Love potion, yo. I got it all.
夏日之恋  青春之恋  破碎之恋
Summer love, young love, anti-love.
只要用手指头蘸一丁点  然后奇迹就发生了
You just got to put a little on your fingers and pow!
我需要那种魔药
I need that potion.
开个价吧
How much would it cost?
拿这只松鼠作为报酬怎么样
Um, would you accept squirrels as payment?
这可不行
No way.
可能你自以为造福了别人
You might think you know what's best for people,
但这玩意儿会引发重大的社会后果
but this stuff can have major social consequences.
正因如此  只有我这样严谨的专家才能使用
That's why it can only be used by a serious expert.
小爱神
Love God!
在我脸上签个名吧
Sign my face.
除非你也给我签  宝贝儿  一起狂欢吧
Only if you sign mine, baby. Let's get weird!
介意我在这薯条里头加点料吗
Mind if I add a little something to these fries?
我看不出有何不可
I don't see why not.
嚯  怎么感觉你整个人都变得可爱多了
Whoa! Did your whole thing suddenly get a lot more likeable?
你好像也没我印象中那么俗了
You don't seem as needy as I used to think you were.
你想不想离开这儿  然后
Hey, you wouldn't want to maybe get out of here and,
或许  在公共场合热吻怎么样
I don't know, go kiss in public a lot?
不知道为什么  我挺想的
For some reason, I do.
状态更新
Status update.
你猜怎么着  管它呢
You know what? Forget it.
也许我该把视线从手机上移开了
Maybe I should stare at something other than my phone for a while.
牵手成功
Match made!
好啦  谁准备好享受今年夏天
All right, who's ready for the best
最棒也是最昂贵的夜晚啊
and most overpriced day of our summer?
好啦
Yay! All right!
我带了满满一包什锦果仁
I brought a baggie of trail mix
还有哨子  以防大家走散
and safety whistles in case we get separated.
无聊
Lame.
这孩子真是出类拔萃
This kid is a champion.
现在就差谭布丽了
We're just waiting on Tambry.
咱可不能丢下她先走
Can't leave without Tambry.
抱歉啊  同志们  谭布丽现在正忙着呢
Sorry, guys, but Tambry's a little busy at the moment.
看我的小眼神
Wink. Wink.
啥意思啊  你为啥要眨眼
What does that mean? Why are you winking?
这么说吧  她和罗比可正打得火热哟
Let's just say she and Robbie took a trip to Smoochville.
现在大家都开心啦
Now everyone's happy!
什么  罗比和谭布丽
Wait. Wait. Robbie and Tambry?
这绝对不可能
This can't be happening.
为什么啊
How's that?
他明知道我喜欢她
He knew I liked her.
他怎么能这样做啊
How could he do this?
喂喂  打住  你喜欢谭布丽
Whoa, hold it. You like Tambry?
而且你竟然告诉罗比却不告诉我
And you told Robbie but not me?
每次我对女孩一心动  你就笑话我
You always make fun of my crushes, man.
这就是好基友该做的事情啊  才子
That's what we do, genius.
这还真像是谭布丽干出的事儿
This is so like Tambry to do this.
背着我跟我的前男友约会
Date my ex behind my back.
我要把她头上那撮紫毛扯下来
I'm gonna tear her highlights out.
各位  各位  淡定啊
Guys! Guys! Calm down.
咱们要赶不上演唱会了
We're gonna be late for the concert.
通知  孩子
Uh, news flash, kid.
我不打算去演唱会了
I'm not going to the concert.
至少不跟这家伙一起去
Not with him.
嘿  这对你来说不成问题  因为我不去了
Hey, that won't be a problem 'cause I'm out.
我也不去了
Me, too.
别走啊  别走啊  我就只有你们了
Wait! Wait! This group is all I have!
我不想像以前一样孤身一人
Don't make me go back to having no friends!
大伙儿
Guys!
牵手  成功了吗
Match... made?
别走啊  哥们儿  别碰我家的邮箱
Wait, guys. Don't go. Not my mailbox!
瞧瞧你们干的好事
What did you just do?!
我长久以来忍受他们的作弄
I've let these guys pick on me for years
就为了让大家能在一起玩
to keep this group together.
现在他们彻底分崩离析了
And now they've totally fallen apart.
我们也都希望大家能一块儿玩儿啊
But we were all starting to finally hang out together.
我也是大家的一分子啊
I was one of the gang.
除非你现在就把那一对儿拆散
Well, unless you can break up Robbie and Tambry immediately,
否则就没有什么“大家”了
there is no gang.
我也再没有朋友了
I have no more friends.
你们也是一样  我要把这些都吃了
And neither do you. I'm gonna eat this.
梅宝  我不是说过吗  别掺和罗比的私事
Mabel, what did I tell you about staying out of Robbie's personal life?
是啊  我知道啊
I know. I know!
我只不过是想做个好红娘而已
I just wanted to be a good matchmaker.
我就不应该偷拿爱神的爱情魔药
I never should have gotten love potion from the Love God.
等等  爱情魔药
Wait, love potion?
如果你对他俩施了魔法  难道就不能撤销吗
If you did a spell, then can't you, like, undo it?
对呀
That's it!
如果我撤消了魔法
If I undo the spell,
那么大家就又能一起玩了
then everyone will be friends again.
但是我需要你的帮助
But I'm gonna need your help.
还有就是  你穿V领衫难看死了
Also, you are not pulling off that V-neck.
我知道
I know.
快烧掉
Burn it!
伍德斯迪克音乐节
赶快把气球做好  苏斯
Balloon faster, Soos!
音乐节结束之前这玩意儿必须飞上天
We need this thing up in the air before the festival ends.
话说把火焰和挂着的衣服绳子
Are you sure that that open flame should be
放那么近是不是太危险了
that close to that dangling cloth and rope?
我的安全意识你别瞎操心
I'm sure about everything.
现在把煤油当润滑油加到发动机齿轮里
Now lube up those engine gears with some kerosene.
多放点煤油
More kerosene!
各位快回来  别闹了
Unh! Come back, guys! Come on.
门票花了我一百块钱  我把手表都卖了
The tickets were 100 bucks. I sold my watch.
快跟我去看演唱会吧
You got to come to the concert.
难道还得看这幅景象
Ew, and have to look at that?
别恶心我了
No, thanks.
他们都开始左搂右抱了
Ugh, they're doing that couple hug-walk.
二位  这大庭广众的
Guys, you're in public.
别人都看得见啊
People can see you.
迪普  快跟我来
Dipper. Come on.
爱神  该爱神调音了啊
Love God. Sound check for Love God.
下面就是见证奇迹的时刻
Let's make some miracles happen.
追星族们  帮我整整头发
Groupies, bed-head me.
疯狂的爱神马上驾到
Love God's about to get crazy.
哎呀  好了
Whoa. Hey, all right.
机会总算来了
Now's our chance.
来看看都有啥
Here we go. Let's see.
清纯之恋  种间之恋  乡村音乐之恋
Puppy love, inter-species love, love of country music.
真恶心
Ew.
噢  破碎之恋
Oh! Anti-love.
用于逆转爱情魔药作用
To reverse the effects of love potion,
将其喷洒在受害者身上即可观其心碎之态
simply spray on your victim and watch their heart die on the inside.
我觉得挺好啊
Sounds good to me.
喂
Hey!
你就是那个偷我东西的小鬼
You're the one who's been stealing my stuff.
我可一点都不爱被偷
I am not loving this.
对不起  我做错事了  现在要弥补过错
I'm sorry. But I made a mistake and I have to fix it.
孩子  都跟你说了
Kid, I tried to tell you.
这些东西实在是太危险了
This stuff is way too dangerous.
以神的名义发誓  不能让你
On my oath as a God, I cannot let you--
哎  你们往哪儿跑呢
Oh, hey, where did you just go?
对不起啦  爱神
I'm sorry, Love God!
为了朋友我豁出去了
But it's for the good of my friends!
快给我回来
Come back here!
迪普  接好
Dipper, catch!
把那俩小屁孩抓起来
Get those kids!
不许动
Halt!
别想在我们面前“胡”来
We mustache you to move!
漂亮
Good one.
呼  谢谢大家
Ooh! Thank you.
别  别  别  别到处乱摸了
No, no, no, everyone's touching everything!
快把魔药给我还回来
Give me back the potion!
哟  你好啊
Oh, hey, what's up?
来  磁带送你了
Here, have a cassette.
我去  小翅膀快扇啊
Dang it. Fly, tiny wings.
快带我上天
Get up there. Oh!
好久都没用过翅膀了啊
I haven't had to use these in a long time.
嬉皮茶
迪普  快看
Dipper. Look.
只要往他们后脑勺一喷
Just one clean shot to the back of their heads
就万事大吉了
and everything's fixed.
不是我不讲理  是你们逼我的
Sorry, kids, but you've left me no choice.
旧日情殇重现
Visions of heartbreak past!
梅宝  我们回来啦
We're back, Mabel.
我们现在喜欢你了
We like you now.
对啊  肯定的  绝对喜欢你
Yes. Definitely. Absolutely.
哈  你就这点雕虫小技
Ha! You really think we'd fall for that?
当然啦  你们全都可以嫁给我
Sure  you can all marry me!
哟  十块钱上的哥们儿
Oh! Guy from the $10 bill.
我都忘了我喜欢过你嘞
I forgot I had a crush on you.
我靠  梅宝  那些都是幻象
Dang it, Mabel. They're not real.
梅宝  快把瓶子给我
Just give us the bottle, Mabel.
梅宝  别啊
Mabel, don't!
总算完事了
It's finally done.
等这帮傻蛋看到这气球
When these idiots see this balloon,
就会明白我多喜欢孩子的
they'll understand that I love young people.
“我爱孩子”
"I heart kids."
好了  放上去吧
All right, let 'er rip.
哎呀  一个字母掉了
Oh. Oh, no! A letter rip!
搞什么鬼
What the H?!
我吃孩子
我吃孩子  我们就是孩子啊
I eat kids? But we're kids!
肯定是老天爷的惩罚
It's heaven's punishment
因为我们的品味太次了
for our terrible taste in everything!
妈妈  那个天上飘着的脑袋会吃掉我们吗
Mommy, is the floating head going to eat us?
当然会  查理
Yes, Charlie!
当然会
Yes, he will.
梅宝  那都是法术  别把瓶子给
Mabel, it's a trick! Don't give him the...
拿到手了
Gotcha!
我的小心灵真是太纯洁了
Oh! Curse my oversized heart.
对不起了孩子们  下次明白
Sorry, kids, but that's what happens
见到神要乖乖的不惹事了吧
when you mess with a god.
除非上天派来了个更厉害的家伙  才能与神
Only a greater being from the heavens themselves could possibly stop--
要掉下来了啊
It's coming down!
哦不  真希望没人被砸死
Oh, no. I hope someone didn't die.
对啊  要不然就太可怕了
Yes, that would be awful.
大家都咋咋呼呼啥呢
What's everybody crying about?
老子小时候  飞艇掉得跟雨点子似的
In my day, zeppelins fell from the sky like raindrops.
是他
It's him!
天上飞的那个吓人的老头子
The horrible old man from the sky!
你猜怎么着
You know what?
受年轻人爱戴根本没那么好
Being loved by the youth is overrated.
能把他们吓跑才是真本事
Being feared? Now that's priceless.
爱神  你还好吗
Love God, are you okay?
求你别死  求你别死
Please be immortal. Please be immortal.
小毛孩  我受够了
Dude. I am so over this!
爱神该上台了
Love God to the stage.
听着  小鬼  想要就拿走吧
Aagh! Look, kid, take it, okay?
想喷谁喷谁   我不管了
Spray everyone for all I care.
你不是想拿人生开玩笑么
You want to mess with people's lives?
你不是想当神仙吗
You want to play God?
你就去吧  反正我是当腻了
Do it. 'Cause I'm sick of it.
医生  我要  我要洋葱圈
Medic, I need-- I need onion rings!
好了  梅宝  机会总算来了
Okay, Mabel, now's our chance.
他们俩一分  朋友们就能重聚了
They break up and the whole friend group gets back together.
梅宝
Mabel!
梅宝  我就是想谢谢你
Mabel, I just wanted to thank you.
我跟温蒂分手之后  都快不成人样了
I've been so miserable since Wendy broke up with me
以为我的人生就这么结束了
that I thought my life was over.
但是你说得对
But you were right.
我还是需要继续前进的
I just needed to move on.
我挺高兴的  奇怪吧
I'm... happy? Weird, huh?
罗比  大家都在我们照片下面发评论呢
Robbie, people are commenting on our pictures.
迪普  我觉得还是别这样了
Dipper, maybe we shouldn't do this.
我是说  每次我们对别人的命运乱来
I mean, every time we've played with people's fates,
只会让结果变得更糟
it's only made things worse.
他们真是天生一对啊
They are kind of perfect for each other,
恶心到一起去了
in a gross kind of way.
那我们的小圈子怎么办
But what about our friend group?
或许顺其自然就好了
Well, maybe it'll sort itself out.
总该有个什么事情
I mean, there's got to be something
能把小圈子里的朋友们都召集回来的
that could bring everyone back together.
伙计们  我做了个友谊蛋糕
Guys, I made a friendship cake.
大家都别赌气了好吗
So let's all get over this, okay?
我的蛋糕啊
My cake!
喂  严禁外带食物
Hey! Food from the outside!
快抓住他
Get him!
谁  快看啊
Who! Hey, look.
那不是汤普森么
Is that Thompson?
天啊
Oh, man.
快把那俩打趴下啊  汤普森
Yeah, fight the machine, Thompson!
-朝他们脑袋上丢零食  -别忘了你有牛肉干啊
- Throw snacks at 'em. - Use jerky as a weapon.
汤普森
Thompson!
汤普森  汤普森
Thompson! Thompson!
Thompson! Thompson...
我觉得一切都会好起来的
I think everything just might be all right.
可能某人还真是个红娘小天才呢
Maybe someone up there really is a genius matchmaker.
计划太完美了
All according to plan.
猪羊一家
A goat and a pig.
摇摇和冈珀斯  大喜之日
一对家畜
A couple of livestock
日子幸福和谐又美满
Living the life, stuck together in harmony
猪羊一家  世上谁能想到
A pig and a goat, who in the world thought
让猪和羊住在同一屋檐下
A pig and a goat could be family
爱的力量强大无比
Love so strong, love so big
小猪英俊小羊美丽
Such a beautiful goat and a pig
直至白头偕老
Bound in matrimony now and forever
购杂货又买公寓
Shopping for groceries and buying a condo
一起填写报税表
And filing their taxes together
猪羊一家呀  猪羊一家
Goat and a pig, goat and a pig